Oscar Forner Martinez

I am a senior software engineer with experience in both bare metal and in the cloud, using RESTAPI and GraphQL for processing thousands of requests per second.

You can use an interactive version of my CV by running: docker run -it maitesin/resume

Experience

July 2021

Senior Software Engineer at Sketch

- May 2024

For the first 2 years I worked as the single Backend Engineer for the **Prototype Team**. My duties for the team where to implement all the different Prototype features required such as **assets generation**, **regeneration on-demand**, **invalidation**, **and deletion from S3 buckets**. These features had to be implemented in different number of servies implemented in **Elixir and Go**.

Afterwards, the teams got disolved and we started working on verticals. In my case, I was part of the **Web vertical**. During my time as part of the Web vertical I worked on multiple projects such as **permission groups**, **optimization of the rendering pipeline**, **optimization of the ingestion pipeline**, **workers to remove unused data from S3 buckets**, **etc**. These projects also required to modify or implement services in **Elixir and Go**.

April 2020 - July 2021

Lead Software Engineer at Paack

During my time in Paack I have worked in multiple projects, such as **Warehouse**Management System, Business Rules Engine, New Retailer API, and Communications Service. All of them were developed in Go using PostgreSQL as the database to store the information of the services and they were deployed in **Kubernetes** using **Helm** and **Istio**.

As part of my role as Lead Software Engineer I mentored several people in my team and I was heavily involved in the hiring process of the company.

June 2018 - April 2020

Senior Backend Software Engineer at GlobalSign

As part of my duties in GlobalSign I implemented new functionalities in the **High Performance Platform**, written in **Go**, that served thousands of certificates per second. I also lead the migration of backend storage from **MongoDB** to **PostgreSQL**.

I mentored multiple new-hires and had a highly involved role in the hiring process.

Sept. 2016 - June 2018

Software Engineer at VCA Technology

During my time at VCA Technology I created a **network library** that allows the user to interact with **Boost ASIO** through the **std::stream** interface, added **authentication** to the system, and designed the **configuration migration process**.

In addition, I improved the in-house **toolchain** to use **clang-tidy** for the linting of our code and I lead the usage of **continuous integration** in order to improve the product delivered to the customer, and to reduce the time to market.

April 2015

Software Developer at Programming Research

- Sept. 2016

I worked in two projects during my time at Programming Research.

- -Static analysis of code: Checks if the code has some patterns such as: *undefined behaviour*, *unspecified in the Standard*, and/or *implementation-defined*.
- -Dataflow analysis of code: Checks the complexity of methods, pointer problems, memory handling, etc.

July 2013

Software Engineer at European Bioinformatics Institute

- Apr. 2015

My main duty was to create a RESTful service to allow users to query for information about multiprotein complexes.

Education

2010-2013 Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science; Universitat Jaume I (Spain)

2006-2010 Associate Degree in Computer Science; Universitat Jaume I (Spain)

Programming Languages

Go 8 years of professional experience.

Python 5 years of professional experience.

Elixir 3 years of professional experience.

Technical Skills

CI GitHub Actions, GitLab-Cl, Jenkins.

Databases PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite, MariaDB, and MySQL.

Orchestra. Kubernetes, Docker compose, Helm, and Istio.

Broker SQS, RabbitMQ, and PubSub.

Languages

Spanish Native

English Fluent

oscar.forner.martinez@gmail.com +34 617 60 60 12

Blog: https://oscarforner.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscarforner

GitHub: https://github.com/maitesin